## Filipe Santos

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



## **EDUCATION**

#### **React Certification**

Udemy, Maximilian Schwarzmüller Ongoing

## Node.js, Express & MongoDB Bootcamp

Udemy, Jonas Shmedtman

May 2022

## **Javascript Certification**

Udemy, Jonas Shmedtman

April 2022

## **B.S. Computer Science**

Instituto Superior de Engenharia de Coimbra July 2018

### LANGUAGES

**English B2** French Portuguese **Native** 

#### CONTACT

Phone: +41 78 211 95 96 Email: fd.filipe@gmail.com

Resident Permit: B

LinkedIn: in/filipedsantos

Portfolio: https://portfolio-fsantos.netlify.app/

Address: Ch. du nant-de-crève-coeur 10

1290 Versoix

#### **PROFILE**

A fast-learning, curious, and diligent IT specialist using my skills in software development, such as Java, C/C++, or Android applications. I am also knowledgeable in frontend development, with proficiencies in HTML/CSS, Javascript, and React framework. I graduated in Computer Science and Mathematics and I can work fluently in English, French, and Portuguese.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java, Android SDK, C/C++, SQL, SQLite, MongoDB, HTML/CSS, Javascript, React, Node.js, Express, Docker,

#### SOFT SKILLS

Solutions & Results Oriented, Deep Thinking & analysis, Task & fact-oriented, Focus & attention to detail.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Full Stack Developer - GBN - 03/2022 - Present

Concepting and developing a RESTful API, developed with Node.js, Express, and MongoDB to manage the hardware requests to the IT department.

#### Android Developer - 09/2017 - 02/2018

Internship at Ciengis S.A., creating and developing an Android application from scratch.

Analysis/Design	Development	Testing
Project Scope/SRS	Java	Unit tests
Requirements	Android Studio	Integration tests
Screen layouts	Maven	Fixes
Documentation	Git	Quality

## OTHERS EXPERIENCES

Arce Stores SA - 09/2019 - 12/2021 Blinds installation company, Geneva

Chez Fernandes - 08-2018 - 08/2019

Bakery and Pastry shop, Bex